youtern.com 2012-10-14

# Privacy Policy: Find internships perfect for your career path with our internship search function. See YouTern’s blog for tips on making your internship a success.

**Collection and Use of Personal Information**

“Personal information”. That sounds so… personal. Don’t worry, we won’t ask to become your friend on Facebook. Personal information consists of the details that can be used to identify and contact you in the event that we need to - specifically your name, postal delivery address (where applicable), e-mail addresses, payment methods (e.g., credit card or debit card) and telephone number.

When you register or re-register at our site, we ask you to supply personal information so we can enhance and personalize our services and marketing efforts. We use this personal information to set up your account, process your orders and your payments, and to communicate with you on these and other topics. We also use your e-mail address to send you newsletters, as well as messages about YouTern special offers, events and consumer surveys. If you no longer want to receive the newsletters or other announcements simply contact us at

[support@youyern.com](mailto:Support@YouTern.com) and indicate your preferences (“You’re really great, YouTern! But..... It’s not you… it’s me!”). 

We record your interactions with us, including but not limited to basic site activity (logins, resume updates, for example), payment history and correspondence. We use this information to help us quickly and efficiently respond to inquiries and requests, to troubleshoot and otherwise improve the YouTern site, and to enhance our service offering for our customers. We also provide analyses of our users in the aggregate to prospective partners and advertisers (Don’t worry… all names are changed to protect the innocent).

While using the YouTern service and site, you will have opportunities to post reviews and comments in public forums. This information is made public and is not subject to this policy.

_**We do not and will not sell, rent, distribute, hand off, deliver by bike messenger, broadcast, give, donate, tie to a he lium balloon and set it free, or otherwise disseminate your personal information to anyone.**_ 

YouTern’s registered employers and career centers can access your resume information for review, for the purposes of potentially contacting you regarding an available position. You do have the option within the site to make your resume “anonymous” so your contact information is not visible.

**Links to Other Sites**

The YouTern Web site contains links to sites operated by third parties whose policies regarding the handling of personal information may differ from ours. While we endeavor to associate with reputable sites, YouTern cannot be responsible for the information handling practices of these other sites.  (You should read their Terms & Conditions, too).

**Viewing and Updating Your Information on YouTern**

You are responsible for updating and maintaining the truth and accuracy of the personal information you provide to us relating to your account. If you already registered under a fake name and now that you read this section you feel guilty and you want to go back and update this information, you should do so by visiting the **My Profile** section. You must be signed in to access your profile page.

**Cookies and Other Technology**

_**“C” is for cookie, that’s good enough for me...**_

As you browse the YouTern site, cookies are placed on your computer's hard drive. Cookies are small pieces of data that are sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your hard drive for identification and record keeping purposes. (I know! - don’t you wish your computer could produce REAL cookies?!... like out of the disk drive or something?) In general, cookies can make the web more useful by storing information about your preferences on a particular site. Cookies in and of themselves do not personally identify users, although they do identify a user's computer. If your browser is set to not accept cookies, you will not be able to use some features of the YouTern site. (Non-technical speak: cookies are just computer short-cuts).

In addition to cookies, we use other technologies, including pixel tags, to gather information on how our users interact with our site and to otherwise help us efficiently operate and monitor our site and service. These technologies, show us, for example, popular pages, conversion rates, click-throughs and other information that can be used to improve, operate and monitor our site and our service. Third parties, including consultants we engage and online advertisers, may also use this technology to perform similar services for us as well as to assess their own advertising or services.

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

As I mentioned before, except as otherwise disclosed to you, we will not sell, rent, disclose, tie to a helium balloon, etc. your personal information to third parties.

We use other companies, agents or contractors to perform services on our behalf. For example, we have partnered with other companies to personalize and optimize our Web pages, process credit card transactions, collect debts, analyze and enhance data, including customers' interaction with our site, and process consumer surveys. 

From time to time, we may partner with companies whose products we believe will interest our users. In conjunction with these partners, we may send promotional announcements and/or serve web-based advertisements to our customers on their behalf. 

YouTern also reserves the right to disclose personal information when we reasonably believe disclosure is required by law, (Book ‘em, Dano!) if we reasonably believe disclosure is necessary to establish or exercise legal rights, or in situations involving potential threats to physical safety. In the event that YouTern is acquired by or merged with another company, we reserve the right, to sell or otherwise transfer the personal information we have collected as part of that transaction _provided that such third party continues to honor our privacy policy._ (That last part is especially important to us).

_**If you’ve read this far, I’m really impressed with your patience! You’re almost done!**_

**Security   **

**Here comes some more technical stuff… put on your propeller hat. We take our users’ security very seriously… so you should read it...**

YouTern uses all reasonable administrative, technical and managerial measures to protect your personal information and payment methods from unauthorized access (that’s legalese for “we want to protect you from hackers and spammers”). For example, we utilize Secure Sockets Layering (SSL) digital certificate, an industry-standard protocol that encrypts YouTern user’s data, to register and process payment information with the utmost security. In addition, YouTern uses the PCI Data Security Standard which incorporates the various cardholder security programs previously created by Visa, MasterCard, Discover, and American Express.

You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account information and for restricting access to your computer or mobile device through which you access your YouTern account. Users of public or shared computers (at work, libraries, internet café’s) or unprotected mobile devices (your iPhone) should log out at the completion of each visit to the YouTern Web site. YouTern highly discourages sharing or allowing access of your personal YouTern account with unregistered internet users. 

We strive to provide a safe, secure environment by attempting to limit access to our database to legitimate users, but cannot guarantee that unauthorized parties will not gain access. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information and cannot assume liability for improper access to it. We also cannot control how authorized users store or transfer information downloaded from the database, so you should ensure that you do not post sensitive information to YouTern. By using this Web site, or providing personal information to us through any means, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of this sit

As part of our focus on the safety of your data, we reserve the right to modify or alter your postings on YouTern without notification in terms of removal of email addresses and other contact information in body of the job descriptions. We do this for the further security of our users', so "crawlers" (sounds creepy doesn't it?) or automatic site search programs don't find your email address, or other contact information, out in the open and send it to spammers. (You didn't know spammers did such things did you? Yes. They're not good people.)  

(Keep your friends close… and your passwords closer). Users are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any password and other login information created by themselves, or by YouTern for accessing the site, and are fully responsible for all activities that occur under User's password or account. User agrees to immediately notify YouTern of any unauthorized use of User's password or account or any other breach of security.

**Changes to This Policy**

As we update and expand our services, we may make changes to this policy. You should check back for updates to this policy from time to time. If the changes result in materially less protection for your personal information than that provided in this policy, we will make reasonable efforts to contact you and obtain your consent to the changes. Like our Terms & Conditions, of which this policy is a part, your use of the YouTern website or continued use of our service after our efforts to contact you means that you agree to be bound by such changes.

**Contact**

If you have questions concerning your account, please contact Customer Service at [support@youyern.com](mailto:Support@YouTern.com), and we will be happy to assist you.
